Good morning everybody.
صباح الخير للجميع.
I work with really amazing,
أعمل مع مخلوقات صغيرة ضئيلة مهمشة
little, itty-bitty creatures called cells.
رائعة، تسمى الخلايا.
And let me tell you what it's like
ودعوني أخبركم عن
to grow these cells in the lab.
زراعة هذه الخلايا في المختبر.
I work in a lab where we take cells out of their native environment.
أشتغل في مختبر حيث نأخذ الخلايا من محيطها الأصلي.
We plate them into dishes
ونزرعها في صحون
that we sometimes call petri dishes.
نسميها أحيانا صحون بتري.
And we feed them -- sterilely of course --
ونطعمها -- بالتعقيم طبعا --
with what we call cell culture media -- which is like their food --
بما نسميه الوسط المغذي للخلايا -- والذي هو بمثابة طعامهم --
and we grow them in incubators.
و نزرعها في حاضنات.
Why do I do this?
لماذا أقوم بهذا؟
We observe the cells in a plate,
نعاين الخلايا في رقاقة،
and they're just on the surface.
وتوجد مباشرة على السطح.
But what we're really trying to do in my lab
لكن ما نحاول القيام به حقا في مختبري
is to engineer tissues out of them.
هو هندسة أنسجة انطلاقا منها.
What does that even mean?
ما الذي يعنيه ذلك؟
Well it means growing an actual heart,
حسنا، يعني زراعة قلب حقيقي،
let's say,
لنقل ذلك ،
or grow a piece of bone
أو زراعة قطعة من عظم
that can be put into the body.
التي يمكن أن توضع في الجسم.
Not only that, but they can also be used for disease models.
ليس هذا فقط، لكن يمكنها كذلك أن تستعمل في نماذج المرض.
And for this purpose, traditional cell culture techniques
ولهذا الغرض، تقنيات استنبات الخلايا التقليدية
just really aren't enough.
ليست بالفعل كافية.
The cells are kind of homesick;
تحس الخلايا نوعا ما بالحنين إلى الوطن؛
the dish doesn't feel like their home.
لا تحس أن الصحن هو موطنها.
And so we need to do better at copying their natural environment
وبالتالي نحتاج إلى بذل المزيد من الجهد في نسخ بيئتها الفعلية
to get them to thrive.
لجعلها تنموا.
We call this the biomimetic paradigm --
نسمي ذلك نمط التقليد الحيوي --
copying nature in the lab.
نسخ الطبيعة في المختبر.
Let's take the example of the heart,
دعونا نعتمد مثال القلب،
the topic of a lot of my research.
موضوع الكثير من أبحاثي.
What makes the heart unique?
ما الذي يجعل القلب فريدا؟
Well, the heart beats,
حسنا، القلب ينبض،
rhythmically, tirelessly, faithfully.
بشكل إيقاعي، دون كلل، وبإخلاص.
We copy this in the lab
ننسخ ذلك في المختبر
by outfitting cell culture systems with electrodes.
بتجهيز أنظمة استنبات الخلايا بإلكترودات.
These electrodes act like mini pacemakers
تشتغل هذه الإلكترودات كأجهزة تنظيم ضربات قلب مصغرب
to get the cells to contract in the lab.
لجعل الخلايا تنقبض في المختبر.
What else do we know about the heart?
ما الذي نعرفه غير ذلك حول القلب؟
Well, heart cells are pretty greedy.
حسنا خلايا القلب في غاية الجشع.
Nature feeds the heart cells in your body
تغذي الطبيعة خلايا القلب في جسدك
with a very, very dense blood supply.
بتموين كثيف جدا من الدم.
In the lab, we micro-pattern channels
في المختبر، ننمط القنوات مجهريا
in the biomaterials
في المواد الحيوية
on which we grow the cells,
التي نزرع عليها الخلايا.
and this allows us to flow the cell culture media, the cells' food,
وهذا يسمح لنا بمتابعة المستنبت الخلوي، غذاء الخلايا،
through the scaffolds where we're growing the cells --
عن طريق السقالات التي نزرع فيها الخلايا --
a lot like what you might expect
تشبه كثيرا ما قد تتوقعونه
from a capillary bed in the heart.
من سرير الشعيرات في القلب.
So this brings me to lesson number one:
وهكذا أصل إلى الدرس الأول:
life can do a lot with very little.
تستطيع الحياة القيام بالكثير باستعمال القليل.
Let's take the example of electrical stimulation.
دعونا نأخذ مثال التحفيز الكهربائي.
Let's see how powerful just one of these essentials can be.
دعونا نرى درجة قوة واحدة فقط من هذه المبادئ.
On the left, we see a tiny piece of beating heart tissue
على اليسار، نرى قطعة صغيرة من نسيج قلب نابض
that I engineered from rat cells in the lab.
هندستها من خلايا فأر في المختبر.
It's about the size of a mini marshmallow.
إنها تقريبا بحجم حلوى صغيرة.
And after one week, it's beating.
وبعد أسبوع، إنها تنبض.
You can see it in the upper left-hand corner.
يمكنكم رؤيتها في الركن اليساري في الأعلى.
But don't worry if you can't see it so well.
لكن لا تقلقوا إن لم تستطيعوا رؤيتها جيدا.
It's amazing that these cells beat at all.
إنه من المدهش أن هذه الخلايا تنبض على الإطلاق.
But what's really amazing
لكن المدهش حقا
is that the cells, when we electrically stimulate them,
هو أن الخلايا، حين نحفزها كهربائيا
like with a pacemaker,
مثل جهاز تنظيم ضربات القلب،
that they beat so much more.
بحيث تنبض أكثر.
But that brings me to lesson number two:
لكن ذلك يوصلني إلى الدرس الثاني:
cells do all the work.
الخلايا تقوم بكل العمل.
In a sense, tissue engineers have a bit of an identity crisis here,
بمعنى أن مهندسي الخلايا لديهم نوع من أزمة الهوية هنا،
because structural engineers
لأن مهندسي البنيات
build bridges and big things,
يصنعون الجسور والأمور الكبيرة،
computer engineers, computers,
مهندسو الحواسيب، الحواسيب،
but what we are doing
لكن الذي نقوم به نحن
is actually building enabling technologies for the cells themselves.
هو بالفعل تمكين الخلايا نفسها من الوصول إلى التكنولوجيا.
What does this mean for us?
ما الذي يعنيه ذلك لنا؟
Let's do something really simple.
دعونا نقم بشيء في غاية البساطة.
Let's remind ourselves
دعونا نذكر أنفسنا
that cells are not an abstract concept.
أن الخلايا ليست مفهوما مجردا.
Let's remember that our cells sustain our lives
دعونا نتذكر أن خلايانا تمكننا من الحياة
in a very real way.
بطريقة في غاية الواقعية.
"We are what we eat," could easily be described
"نحن ما نأكله،" يمكن أن يعبر عنها بسهولة
as, "We are what our cells eat."
بـ،"نحن ما تأكله خلايانا."
And in the case of the flora in our gut,
وفي حالة النبات في أحشائنا،
these cells may not even be human.
هذه الخلايا قد لا تكون حتى إنسانية.
But it's also worth noting
لكن ذلك أيضاً يستحق الإهتمام
that cells also mediate our experience of life.
ذلك أن الخلايا تتدخل في تجاربنا الحياتية.
Behind every sound, sight, touch, taste and smell
وراء كل صوت ومرآى وملمس ومذاق ورائحة
is a corresponding set of cells
هناك مجموعة من الخلايا موافقة له
that receive this information
تستقبل هذه المعلومات
and interpret it for us.
وتترجمها لنا.
It begs the question:
وهي سؤالا بالحاح :
shall we expand our sense of environmental stewardship
هل بإمكاننا توسيع إحساسنا بالمسؤولية البيئية
to include the ecosystem of our own bodies?
لتشمل الأنظمة الحيوية في أجسامنا؟
I invite you to talk about this with me further,
أدعوكم إلى التوسع في الحديث حول هذا معي،
and in the meantime, I wish you luck.
وفي الوقت الحالي، أتمنى لكم حظا سعيدا.
May none of your non-cancer cells
وأتمنى ألا تصير أي من خلاياكم الغير مسرطنة
become endangered species.
مخلوقات مهددة بالإنقراض.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)